[cell phone vibrating]
[grunting]
It's mine.
[Rigsby yawns]
Rigsby.
[clears throat]
Oh, hey. Yep.
You got it, boss.
We're up.
- Lisbon?
- Yep.
Oh, no. No, she's gonna
call here next.
- She'll know. Get out.
- Grace, wake up.
How is Lisbon gonna know
I'm with you, hmm?
Right, yeah.
[cell phone ringing]
Leave it.
Mm, no.
- No.
- Get out.
Get out.
Agent Grace Van Pelt.
Hi, boss. What's up?
Mm-hmm. Alright.
[cell phone ringing]
Bosco, and to what do
I owe this pleasure?
You're up.
Where are you at?
[Jane]
'Crime scene. Why?'
Coffee run?
Usual for you, boss?
Tall drip, black.
We need to talk.
- About what?
- Come see me when you get back.
Okay. Look forward to it.
Hey, either of guys
heard from Hicks yet?
No.
Morning. Well, almost morning.
[female #1]
'Good morning, everyone.'
We got a Caucasian male,
50's. Gunshot to the head.
[Cho]
'And tastefully garnished with
an explosion of yellow roses.'
Security guard saw the body,
called Sac PD
but this is a state cemetery,
which is why we're here at, uh..
...Oh-dark-thirty.
Swell spot.
[Cho]
'Check out the stippling.'
'Looks like he was, uh,
shot at close range.'
Yep. And fibers in the wound
indicate clothes were
removed postmortem.
- Hmm.
- What?
You smell nice.
- Is that lilac soap?
- Yeah.
- You got something, Jane?
- Uh, yes, I do.
- Uh, he's naked.
- Let me write that down.
Well, it makes him look
kinda sad, don't you think?
Vulnerable.
- 'A little comic, even.'
- Meaning what?
He was posed like this.
He wasn't just dumped here
willy-nilly.
This is a statement.
Doctor, the mark on
the hand, is that a burn?
Looks more like
a freezer burn, actually.
- Oh.
- Oh?
That explains it.
His liver temp is 45 degrees
'but it's only around
58 in here.'
So, somebody froze
his body in that position
then dumped him here.
Could be a signature.
Maybe a serial pattern.
Lisbon and I will talk
to Bosco about that.
See if he has any
similar incidents.
Yeah, come on.
Let's get out of here.
Let forensics
do their thing.
You smell lovely.
What is that?
Is that lilac?
Uh, yeah. Thanks.
[Jane]
It's pretty.
'Morning, Rebecca. They look
good. One of those for me?'
You know, it's alright to like
me now. Your boss and I made up.
It's okay, Rebecca.
I don't like him, either.
She's a liar.
She loves me.
'Yeah, keep tellin'
yourself that.'
[screaming]
[Lisbon]
'Oh, my God!'
Oh, my God. No.
[Lisbon]
'Sam! Sam!'
He's gone.
- No pulse.
- 'Dyson's dead too.'
[Lisbon]
'Jane, some help?
Get over here, now!'
[Lisbon]
'Press as hard as you can.
Right, right there. There!'
This is Special Agent Cho
we've got agents
down on the fifth floor.
[Lisbon]
Two, three, four..
[Cho]
'Yes, inside the building.'
We're in lockdown
on my authority.
I have three agents down.
I need EMT's.
'Roll SWAT, Sac PD
and CHP, and have them set'
up a perimeter.
Suspects may still be here.
Just lock this
place down now!
[Lisbon]
'Five, six, seven,
eight, nine'
'ten, eleven, twelve,
thirteen, fourteen..
[theme music]
[instrumental music]
[Lisbon]
'Hicks? Bosco?'
Bosco, Hicks.
Stealing major crimes' food.
Violation of penal code
section 484, I believe.
- It didn't have a name on it.
- Uh, this one does.
It's mine.
It's from Cornaro's.
Mm.
Meatball sub's really
their best thing.
You better hope I don't tell
Mandy you went off your diet.
She's in New Hampshire
with her sister all week.
Ah, there you are.
Agent Hicks, your form 41's.
And, boss, the attorney
general's office called about
the Armenian cartel thing.
And you better hope
I don't tell your wife
about you going
off your diet.
[gags]
Breathe, breathe.
Come on.
I got this.
Clear!
Okay, he's back.
[male #1]
'He's bleeding out.
What do we got?'
[female #2]
'There's no breath sounds
on the right side.'
- His pulse is really weak.
- Run IV wide open.
We're code 3.
Let's move.
[indistinct chattering]
You okay?
What do we got?
Lockdown's in full effect,
building-wide.
Same with
the capitol and the DOJ.
Good, Cho's liaising
with the Sac PD
they're setting up
a 2-block perimeter, now.
Nobody gets in or out.
All civilians
are being sent
to the downstairs'
lobby for holding.
SWAT's on their way up. We're
gonna do a sweep room by room.
- Suspects could still be here.
- Get with security.
Check all the camera footage
and set up teams to interview
all of the guards, janitors
and everyone down in the lobby.
You got it.
[Lisbon]
'He's gone. Go on now.'
Jane?
You may be in shock.
Look at me.
There should be three bodies.
There-there's only two.
- Where's Agent Hicks?
- I'll get Cho on that.
Lisbon, maybe we should
just wash up first.
'Come on.'
Come on.
[water splashing]
[intense music]
[splashing continues]
So, you never saw
Hicks this morning?
No, I haven't seen
him since yesterday.
And yesterday
was he angry or upset?
You think Marlon Hicks
could have done this? Oh, no.
We have to check
every angle, Rebecca.
Let's back up.
[Lisbon]
'When you went out
to get the coffee'
did you see
anything unusual?
Somebody who didn't
belong here, maybe?
No. Everything was fine.
It was normal.
'God, I'm sorry.
I'm not helping.'
Um, uh, I was gone
maybe ten minutes
and I, I-I didn't
see anything weird.
Bosco called the team in early
this morning, do you know why?
Well, I thought that maybe it
was the Armenian cartel arrests.
You werethatclose
to making an arrest?
Y-yeah, um, uh, there was,
um, a break this week.
Um, an informant came
through, the boss said.
It was something about,
um, um, um, a warehouse.
[Jane]
'Uh, Lisbon.'
Did forensics come up with
an ID on the frozen man?
I haven't checked in with them.
It's not really
a priority right now, okay?
Okay. I guess.
- You were saying?
- Camera four, also nothing.
- Just an ordinary day.
- Weird, huh?
- These guys are like ghosts.
- Yeah, no kidding.
We checked the building top to
bottom. There's no sign of them.
BFS are dusting every
stairwell and door for prints
but it'll take days
to go through 'em all.
Lisbon said I should see
if you needed a hand here.
Jimmy, go to
camera five now.
[Grace]
'Lobby entrance,
same time code.'
That's Rebecca coming back.
She was gone nine minutes.
30 altogether.
[Rigsby]
'I don't recognize
hat guy here.'
Put him on the list
of people to check out.
Okay, Jimmy, camera six.
The garage entrance.
Mm-hmm.
Hang on.
Something's screwed up here.
Some files are corrupted
on this data drive.
Um, that's not possible.
Our firewalls--
Have been breached.
Camera six and seven.
That's the garage.
[Grace]
'They were disabled remotely.'
Looks like at least
a 30 minute gap.
Which means we have
no way of knowing
who went in or out
via the garage.
Jimmy, get somebody
from IT down here now.
Figure out what
we're dealing with.
Okay, I-I'll tell my boss.
Ten minutes.
It was all over
in ten minutes.
Okay, got it. Thanks, Avila.
I owe you one.
Agent Lisbon,
I spoke to the governor.
I told him that I have
my best team on this one.
- I know you'll do us proud.
- Thanks, boss.
I just reached out
to Sac PD narcotics
about that
Armenian drug cartel that--
In a minute.
I just got word
from the hospital.
- He's not dead?
- No. No, Bosco's in surgery.
But I wanted you
to prepare yourself.
His injuries are
extensive.
'Critical.'
Teresa, I'm, uh, I'm sorry
to ask this, but I need to know
that you're gonna be able
to go on with this case
'no matter what happens.'
If-if you can't,
just let me know
and I'll put
someone else on point.
Not necessary.
You think Sam Bosco's gonna
let a little lead stop him?
Please.
I hope you're right.
Good luck.
Nothing on Hicks.
I had a uni run by his house,
he's not there.
- No car in the driveway.
- I've got something.
You know that
Armenian drug cartel that Bosco
was close to nailing? It's run
by a guy named Michael Assanian.
Oh-ho, bad guy.
Outside of the Mexicans
biggest heroin distributor
on the west coast.
Bosco must've spooked him. He
left the country three days ago.
So, maybe he leaves town
to keep himself clean
while his people kill Bosco.
Yeah, makes sense.
Kill the team, kill the case.
It's worth checking out.
Lisbon, did we get
an ID on the man
from the cemetery yet?
What's with you and this case?
Oh, it's just a feeling.
You think it's
connected to Bosco?
- Maybe.
- 'How?'
- Hard to say, I..
- Fine. Cho, call it up.
'Forensics might have
posted something by now.'
- Thank you.
- Run down this informant.
See if he's got anything for us.
Lauro in narcotics said
you could use his name.
Yeah, will do.
Forensics says cemetery guy's
'fingerprints belong to'
'a Dr. Towlen Morning'
'age 55, Stockton.'
Towlen Morning.
Jane?
Cho, with me.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
Oh, no.
Hicks.
[heavy breathing]
How did you know
it was Red John?
Towlen Morning was
the family doctor
for Janet
and Carter Peak.
Peaks were Red John's
third and fourth victims.
Carter presumed
to be the fourth.
They never
found his body.
That was nine years ago.
Why attack the CBI today?
Yeah, it's puzzling.
I'm Red John,
why do I kill Morning
and Hicks
and attack Bosco's team?
[Jane]
Carter and Janet Peak.
Nine years ago.
Carter and Janet peak. Nine.
Nine years ago,
I'm a lot less experienced.
Something went wrong with Carter
and Janet Peak. A mistake.
And he fixed it, but somehow
now, it's come undone.
Hicks came to see
the doctor for a reason.
He was checking
something out.
Red John killed him for it.
Killed them all.
Except for Bosco, I mean.
Bosco had a lead in the Red John
case.
Cho, go inside,
check the doctor's files
for Carter and Janet Peak.
X-rays, labs, everything.
Why did Bosco want
the medical reports?
What did he know?
He's in ICU
in a medically induced coma.
He's not gonna
tell us anything.
- I know. I know.
- The case files will.
Van Pelt, have BFS
search Bosco's office
for any new evidence
or notes in the Red John file.
And you and Rigsby start working
with the secretary, Rebecca.
Mm-hmm.
[instrumental music]
Hey, boss.
Nothing from Rebecca.
The BFS techs are
still taking apart
Bosco's office, but so far--
- Is Jane back?
- 'I haven't seen him.'
- Find him, would you?
- Yeah.
[Minelli]
'Special Agents
Nick Martinez and Mark Dyson'
'died at the scene here.'
And Special Agent Marlon Hicks
was found dead
at a secondary crime scene.
Special Agent Samuel Bosco
remains in critical condition.
We are devoting every resource
to this investigation.
And I promise, I promise
the agents' families
we will not rest..
...till we bring
the perpetrator to justice.
Special Agent Minelli,
our condolences.
Would you describe your
feelings at this terrible time?
Wow, Meredith, that..
You media guys,
that's just dis..
You know, for eight years
I've put up with the idiotic
questions of the media
and I've never said squat.
But today, I must
tell you, Meredith..
...you've really set a new
standard in horse's assery.
You people have
no conceptof what we do.
We go into dark,
horrible places
alone and afraid
'and we do it with no money'
with broken-down vehicles with..
...computers that have
more viruses than a $10 whore.
How? Good people.
And I lost three
good people today
and a fourth who's
in critical condition
and you ask me
how I'm feeling.
I'm feelingsad..
...you...moron.
Any other questions?
Okay, then.
Good day to you.
Elizabeth, carry on.
Virgil.
Horse's assery? Nice.
They shouldn't
have done that.
Hey, you told them the truth.
I did.
Felt good.
Stick with us, boss.
We need you.
Okay. Yes.
I gotta run. You got this?
Go.
[indistinct chattering]
Evening, gentlemen.
- Hi.
- You are?
- Oh, I'm sorry. Uh..
Patrick Jane, CBI.
I'm a friend of his.
- 'Uh, how's he doing?'
- He's not good.
The next two days
should tell us a lot.
Oh, he was in such pain.
Is he getting enough morphine?
He should be.
Looks good. Call me if
you need anything else.
Will do. Thanks, doc.
[Lisbon]
'What are you doing?'
Unplugging his morphine.
I'd ask a doctor to do it, but
I think I know what they'd say.
- Are you crazy?
- 'Yes.'
That's exactly
what they'd say.
They wouldn't understand
the moral imperative here.
Bosco is the only person
that can tell us what
he found on Red John.
And he may die,
we need to wake him up
and have him tell us everything
he knows while he still can.
[machine beeping]
- Y-you can't do that.
- Why not?
Morphine doesn't
make him any better.
- It just stops the pain.
- Yes, that's what it does.
Pain is nothing.
Pain means he's still alive.
We need him now,
Lisbon.Now.
He's useless to us
when he's dead.
- Shut up! He's gonna live.
- Maybe and maybe not.
- God, you're a cold bastard.
- Oh, please.
Y-y-you need
to think logically.
He would want
us to do this.
How could you know what he would
want? You don't even know him.
But you do, if he had
to suffer pain to stop Red John
he would do that. You know
that he would. You know that.
What's all the commotion?
What the..
Did you touch that machine?
No.
[Minelli on TV]
'Good people.'
And I've lost three
good people today..
[Grace]
'Is Lisbon with you?'
No.
What's going on?
We got a hit...on Bosco's
cell phone records.
Just before the attack
Bosco called a cop
down in Cloverville,
not far from Stockton.
Cop told me when they
tore down an old strip mall
last week, they found a body
buried in the foundation.
Body?
The cop who posted the bulletin
said he got a call from Bosco
saying he'd go
and check it out.
What body?
This one.
Cloverville PD
e-mailed a copy of the x-rays.
John Doe, 30's.
See here? His head was
almost cut off. Vicious.
- Then there's this.
- What's that?
- 'His leg.'
- He's missing a leg?
The coroner told the cop
it was not part of the attack.
A much earlier amputation,
he said. Distinctive.
The files we got from
Dr. Morning's office
this matches an x-ray
we found there.
Carter Peak.
Carter Peak, retired army
lost his right leg
during the First Gulf War.
They found the missing
Red John victim.
Better still.
This is Red John's mistake.
This is it. He made
a mistake and this is it.
[Jane narrating]
Killing Carter Peak
wasn't Red John's MO.
He was a man who was
killed with his wife.
His body was removed
from the scene.
It is unlike any of Red John's 14 other murders.
Maybe, Carter
returned unexpectedly
maybe, there was a struggle.
[Jane]
'So, Peak's body resurfaces.'
Red John hears about it somehow,
and it upsets him.
A, how does he
hear about the body?
Off the bulletin, I guess.
It was statewide.
And B, why does it upset him?
There's evidence on
Carter Peak's body.
That's why he tried
to make it disappear.
Damning evidence, like DNA.
We gotta get to Cloverville.
The cement matrix preserved
the body remarkably well.
We were able to run
a full DNA crime kit.
Hair, skin under
the fingernails, etcetera.
We need someone
sitting on this place 24/7
until we can move
the body up to Sacramento.
Whoops.
Uh, my bad.
Wow!
That's weird.
Yeah, it is.
Where's the body, doc?
Uh, let me,
let me check the log here.
Okay, you guys
gotta get your signals
straightened up in Sacramento.
CBI already picked up
the body night before last.
- CBI did?
- Yeah.
Night shift logged it,
right here.
California Bureau
of Investigation, an Agent Rojo.
The body, samples.
Uh, everything we had,
it looks like.
See for yourself.
Arrived at 2:15 a.m.
with a meat wagon.
The night before the CBI attack.
I can get you photos, though.
We usually keep a set.
But the crime scene kit,
the DNA samples..
- What about the DNA?
- Well, I'm telling ya.
I-it should have all gone with
your guy. That's procedure.
He wasn't our guy.
Red John?
Call in your night shift person.
I-it's important that we get
an idea of what this, uh..
...Agent Rojo looks like.
[knock on door]
You wanted to see me, boss?
Sit down, please.
Bosco's doing better.
I talked to his doctor.
Good.
That's good.
You okay, boss?
Is this about before
at the press conference?
No.
Yes.
I, um..
I have something to tell you,
Teresa. Something important.
[knock on door]
What is it, agent?
Sorry to interrupt
but I've been going through
the security footage, trying to
ID everyone going in and out.
[Grace]
'This is time coded
for this morning'
'right before the attack.'
'According to employee support
services, that's Amblyn Demott.'
'An analyst on four.'
So what?
Demott went on
maternity leave last month.
She had her baby yesterday.
'There's no way she could be
where that camera says she was.'
Someone switched the footage.
We can't trust
anything on any camera.
[Cho]
'You transferred the body
to the custody of a CBI agent?'
- Yeah.
- 'Describe this agent.'
Dark hair, not that tall,
kinda dumpy, olive-complected.
Wore these heel that clicked.
[Cho]
'A woman?'
Wore a thing, a...
what's it, in her hair.
- A Barrette.
- 'Right. Barrette.'
Hey, sweetie.
Okay.
Here you go.
That's for you.
- Have a nice day.
- Thank you.
- Hi, Rich.
- Hi.
- Hello, Barney. How you doing?
- Hey, Rebecca.
[ECG machine beeping]
[whispering]
Hey, boss.
Boss? Hey.
[intense music]
[Dyson]
'Weren't you heading
to Cloverville?'
Uh, as soon as I brief Jane.
Samuel Bosco Jr.
getting soft.
- 'Hey!'
- Screw you, Martinez.
Hey, guys.
Look what I have.
Aw, you're the best.
Did you get the coffee?
[Bosco]
'Rebecca?'
- You okay?
- A-okay, boss.
[gunshot]
Rebecca.
[Bosco groaning]
[gunshot]
[groaning]
Red John says hi.
[gunshot]
[whispers]
Hi, boss.
Boss.
Hey.
[Lisbon]
Don't move. Drop it now.
[Rebecca grunts]
[Lisbon]
'Bitch.'
You bitch.
Don't move, don't breathe
and don't you smile at me.
[Rebecca chuckles]
What the hell's
with all the balloons?
What are you guys doing here?
[Lisbon]
'Get her outta here.'
[helicopter whirring]
[instrumental music]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[Rebecca sighs]
[music continues]
[Jane sighs]
How long are they
gonna sit there?
Shh.
What's your
favorite kind of music?
Mr. Jane, please.
I know your games.
You don't care
what type of music I like.
I was just making conversation.
Getting to know you.
Well, you want
to know how I could do
such terrible things
for Red John.
Oh, I know that stuff.
Unhappy childhood, sexually
abused by a close relative.
'Cutting or some other
self-abuse.'
Self-medicating,
self-loathing, blah, blah.
E-everyone you ever met
made you feel ashamed.
Ashamed of that ugly darkness
festering inside you.
But he didn't.
He made you strong.
He made you feel
proud of that darkness.
Yes, he did.
'He gave your life
purpose and meaning'
and, uh, love.
[Rebecca]
'And you're very much
like him, you know.'
The way you look at people
and see right through them.
That is just spooky.
I want you to think of this
tonight before you go to sleep.
You are nothing to him
but a useful object.
He is not a good man.
You are so wrong.
He is a very good man.
He's on a mission..
...of love and enlightenment.
He tortures and kills women.
[Rebecca]
Don't you see?
Without death..
...there's no life.
[Rebecca]
'Without darkness,
there's no light.'
- Look at you.
- Me?
'Well, until your wife
and your daughter were killed'
'you were blind, weren't you?'
You were living an illusion.
But Red John opened your eyes.
And now you see the world
for what it truly is.
- Oh.
- 'Mm.'
How did you first meet him?
I'm not telling you
anything about him.
You will.
You'll wake up one day
horrified of what you've done..
...and you will
tell me everything.
No, never.
I love Red John.
And he loves me and I will
never betray that trust.
One day.
But I will tell you that
I like all kinds of music.
Especially country.
And I have a cat named Rex.
And I collect porcelain frogs.
Don't ask me why.
It's just a quirk really.
Well, the psychologist
will want to talk to you next.
He'll have
a field day with that.
But I'm as sane
and as healthy as can be.
- I really am.
- I know.
I do have one question
before you go, Rebecca.
After you took Carter Peak's
body and all the DNA samples..
...why did Red John have
you attack Bosco's team?
There was really no need.
- The evidence was destroyed.
- You know why.
- No.
- 'Oh, you don't?'
Oh, Red John thought
you'd understand.
I got rid
of Bosco and his team..
...so that you could
have the case back.
'Red John misses you.'
And...it's what you wanted too.
'Isn't it?'
We're done here.
[door opens]
Very interesting
talking to you, Rebecca.
Likewise.
I guess I'll see you around.
Yeah.
[Peter Bradley Adam
singing "Darkening Sky"]
[no audio]
♪ Oh come with me
forever my love ♪
♪ Under the darkening sky ♪
♪ Come hide with me ♪
♪ I'll save you my love ♪
♪ Hear me I beg for your life ♪
♪ Her hair is damp ♪
♪ Her skin has turned cold ♪
♪ There's hardly
a sound as she bleeds ♪
♪ Oh stay my love ♪
♪ Please open your eyes ♪
♪ And promise me
you'll never leave ♪
♪ Oh my love ♪
♪ Stay my love.. ♪♪
[indistinct radio chatter]
[man on radio]
'Prisoner is down. She's down.'
Don't touch her!
[panting]
He poisoned her.
[indistinct]
[ECG machine beeping]
Mandy. You get a hold of her?
[Lisbon]
'All the flights
out of Boston were delayed.'
'She's in the air now.'
She'll be here soon.
It's alright.
You're gonna be okay.
It's gonna be okay.
Teresa.
Don't lie to me.
I can tell when you're lying.
You are.
Look, you will be.
You'll be okay.
I'm a cop.
You're a bad liar.
Your eyes give you
away every time.
Honest eyes.
Sam.
Tell me the truth.
[Lisbon sighs]
You lost a lot of blood.
The doctors don't think
you're gonna make it.
I'm gonna say it, then.
The doctors better be right.
I love you, Teresa.
I love you, too.
No. I mean, I love you.
I know what you mean.
It had to be said.
Is Jane here?
[Bosco]
'For the record,
I'm very pissed off about this.'
Can't blame you.
- Sam, uh--
- We don't have time to be nice.
Red John makes mistakes.
This proves it.
You will catch him.
Yes, I will.
Do me a favor.
When you catch him,
don't arrest him.
Kill the son of a bitch.
That's the plan.
Good.
Listen.
[whispers indistinctly]
[ECG machine
beeping erratically]
Bosco?
Sam.
[machine flat lining]
- You weren't at the funeral.
- I was there.
I stayed in the back.
You're quitting?
I tried to
tell you before, but..
Anyway, I prefer retiring.
Full pension.
I got my 20 and then some.
Okay, then.
We'll stay here
and catch the bad guys
while you go fishing.
Lisbon,
in my eight years as SAC
I've lost four agents,
all of them this week.
You should've just quit
last week. It's too late now.
No.
It's time.
You, uh, you take care
of your people.
They're good kids.
Keep an eye on Jane.
If he screws up
too bad, shoot him.
There's not a court in the land
that would convict you.
Mm.
[clears throat]
[sighs]
Hey.
I heard about Minelli.
I'm sorry.
Jane..
...you and Bosco..
...at the hospital..
...what'd he say?
Well, he, uh..
He told me to
look after you.
That's all?
No.
He said that
if I didn't look after you
he'd come back and haunt me.
Total nonsense, of course.
But, uh, it wasn't
the right time to correct him.
Tequila?
Bosco's favorite.
Pint of scotch,
left of the fridge
top shelf,
behind the ramen.
Yeah.
To Sam Bosco.
A damn fine agent.
It was a nice service.
Nice music.
Not a fan of the bagpipes.
[Grace]
'Really? I love 'em.'
They're so...lonely.
It was a nice service.
[Rigsby humming
"Amazing Grace"]
♪ Amazing grace ♪
♪ How sweet the sound ♪
♪ That saved a wretch ♪
♪ Like me ♪♪ Like me ♪
♪ I once was lost ♪
♪ But now am found ♪
♪ Was blind but now I see ♪♪
[instrumental music]
[sighs]
[music continues]
[male narrator]
Stay tuned for scenes
from our next episode.
[theme music]